ANEŽKA KLUSTOVÁ

Email: a.klustova20@imperial.ac.uk Mobile: (+44) 77 2903 6069

CURRENT POSITION

Imperial College London (ICL), United Kingdom

10/2020 - Present

High Energy Physics Research (PhD), President's Scholar

Supervised by Prof Morgan Wascko and Dr Abbey Waldron.

Measurement of the nuclear dependence in inclusive antineutrino scattering with MINERvA in 1D and 2D. Lead geometry, simulation, and reconstruction developer for the near detector gaseous argon prototype TOAD in the test beam at Fermilab. Commissioning, assembly, testing, and operation of TOAD. Attended HEP postgraduate lectures (including journal club), and professional skills development courses. Expected year of graduation: 2024.

EDUCATION

University College London (UCL), United Kingdom

2016 - 2020

MSci Natural Sciences, Physics and Inorganic & Materials Chemistry

1st Class Honours (87.5%), Dean's List Commendee

MSci Thesis: Exotic Contributions to Neutrinoless Double Beta Decay, supervised by Prof Frank Deppisch. Theoretical investigation of Beyond the Standard Model processes mediating neutrinoless double beta decay, specifically scalar and vector Majoron assisted decays, and demonstrating that two neutrino double beta decay can be used as a probe to investigate New Physics.

Relevant modules: Particle Physics (94%), Quantum Field Theory (88%), Advanced Quantum Theory (99%), Mathematical Methods I, II, and III (85%, 83%, 91%), Scientific Communication and Computing (86%), Research Software Engineering with Python (87%), Inorganic Chemistry (86%), Chemistry of Materials (82%)

National University of Singapore (NUS), Singapore

2018 - 2019

Awarded study abroad placement.

Gymnázium J. K. Tyla, Hradec Králové, Czech Republic

2012 - 2016

Maturita: Mathematics (1), Physics (1), Chemistry (1), English (1), Czech (1).

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Fermilab, Illinois, USA

09/2022 - Present

Visiting Researcher

- · Commissioning, assembly, and operations of the near detector gaseous argon prototype for DUNE (Teststand of an Overpressure Argon Detector, TOAD).
- · Geometry, simulation, and reconstruction development for the test detector.

CERN, the European Organization for Nuclear Research, Switzerland

06/2019 - 08/2019

- Summer Research Student, Neutrino Platform
- Supervised by Dr Davide Sgalaberna and Dr Umut Kose.
 R&D of an innovative SiPM calibration system for the T2K scintillator tracker detector and possibly DUNE; gained theoretical background in neutrino oscillation physics.
- · Set up experiments and designed components in CAD, measured MPPC characteristics and the efficiency of light distribution through scintillating fibres, analysed data in ROOT.
- · Attended a series of lectures covering wide range of topics in the fields of theoretical and experimental particle physics and computing.

UCL Physics Department, United Kingdom

06/2018 - 08/2018

Summer Research Student, High Energy Physics Group

- · Supervised by Dr Cheryl Patrick and Prof David Waters.
- · Participated in the development of the SuperNEMO validation strategy software using C++ ROOT library, analysed multiple simulated data from neutrinoless double-beta decay events and background processes, and compared them to reference distributions.
- · Gained theoretical background in physics of neutrinoless double-beta decay process.

Sotio a.s., Czech Republic

06/2017 - 08/2017

Process Development Intern

- · Carried out cytometric and cell culture statistical data analysis, and cell culture modelling
- · Participated in the preparation of active cellular immunotherapy treatment, worked in clean premises (GLP training)

Czech Technical University in Prague, Czech Republic

2015 - 2016

Research Intern, Faculty of Nuclear Sciences and Physical Engineering

- · Studied the dynamic behaviour of nuclear reactors working on school reactor VR-1
- · Analysed theoretically predicted and experimentally collected data using Python

Academy of Sciences of the Czech Republic, Czech Republic

2014 - 2015

Open Science Research Intern, Institute of Physics

- · Studied and experimentally determined the solar cells efficiency based on the depth of dopant material using open circuit method, analysed theoretically predicted and experimentally collected data
- · Presented results at the Open Science Expo 2015 in Prague and received Honourable Recognition for work with public

AWARDS, HONOURS AND FUNDING

NuInt 2022 Accommodation Grant

10/2022

Full accommodation stipend to give a talk at NuInt 2022, Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea.

ICL President's PhD Scholarship

2020 - Present

Full tuition fees and generous stipend for PhD place at ICL for high achieving undergraduates showing excellent academic performance and promising research potential with challenging programme that complements research opportunities with professional development and networking within an elite cohort.

UCL Mathematical & Physical Sciences Dean's List Commendee

2020

Commends outstanding academic performance by graduating students, equivalent to the top 5 % of student achievement in the faculty.

Kellner Family Foundation Scholar

2016 - 2020

Highly competitive scholarship for talented Czechs studying at the world's best universities.

Honourable Recognition for work with public at the Open Science Expo

2015

Member of The Union of Czech Mathematicians and Physicists

2012 - Present

Awarded membership for excellency in subject competitions.

ICL Department of Physics, United Kingdom

10/2021 - Present

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Currently teaching 3rd year Nuclear and Particle Physics seminars (second term 2022/23).

Demonstrated 3rd year undergraduate labs of Computational Physics (first term 2021/2022).

TALKS, POSTERS AND OUTREACH

NuInt 2022, Seoul, South Korea

10/2022

Invited talk about flux simulation and prediction at MINERvA. Poster presentation about studying nuclear dependence in inclusive antineutrino scattering with MINERvA. Received full accommodation stipend.

President's Scholars Symposium, ICL

07/2022

Poster about introduction to neutrino physics, neutrino interactions, MINERvA experiment and analysis motivation.

Postgraduate Symposium, Department of Physics, ICL

07/2022

Poster overview of an inclusive antineutrino scattering analysis.

New Perspectives 2022, Fermilab, USA

06/2022

'MINERvA in 10 Minutes' invited talk on behalf of the MINERvA collaboration.

Neutrino 2022, Virtual Seoul

05/2022

Poster on current progress of studying nuclear dependence in inclusive antineutrino scattering with MIN-ERvA.

APS April Meeting 2022, New York City, USA

04/2022

Parallel talk on current progress of studying nuclear dependence in inclusive antineutrino scattering with MINERvA.

OWAN21 Workshop, Institute of Physics, UK

10/2021

Quick-fire talk on inclusive antineutrino scattering with MINERvA.

Outreach and community engagement:

- 1 social mobility + diversity outreach talk to school pupils aged 15+ (2017)
- 1 science communication talk to school pupils aged 15+ (2020)

SUPERVISION

Mr Alan LI, Ms Hongting NIU, Mr Mingze YAN, Ms Qirui ZHAO, ICL

05/2022 - 06/2022

- Supervised Year 1 students working on 'Building and optimising a multi-stage coil accelerator'

Ms Alina IMYSHENEKOVA, St Paul's Girls' School

06/2021 - 08/2021

- Summer research experience in particle physics

TRAINING AND EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

AEPSHEP 2022, Pyeongchang, South Korea

10/2022

Asia Europe Pacific School of High Energy Physics with 33 lectures and every-day discussion sessions, supporting international collaboration between PhD students from all around the world. Included poster session.

SLAC Summer Institute, Stanford University – Virtual

08/2022

Two-weeks long summer programme with virtual lectures and discussion on 'Golden Opportunities: Puzzles and Surprises - Past Future'.

STFC HEP Summer School, University of Oxford, UK

09/2021

Two-weeks long school aimed at UK-based experimental particle physics PhD at the end of their first year of

training, consisting of lectures, tutorials and related problem sheets covering Quantum Field Theory, Quantum Electrodynamics and Quantum Chromodynamics, the Standard Model and various phenomenological topics. Included poster sessions.

Neutrino Interaction School, DUNE

06/2021 - 07/2021

Series of classes, talks and hands-on activities introducing neutrino-interaction physics, including interaction cross-section measurement, evaluating systematic uncertainties and interaction modelling within DUNE.

MINERvA 101 Week 06/202

Series of talks and hands-on activities introducing neutrino-interaction physics, including interaction cross-section measurement, evaluating systematic uncertainties and interaction modelling within MINERvA.

DUNE Computing Training

05/2021

Introduction to data volumes at FNAL, basic overview of art and LArSoft, development of configuration files to control batch jobs, grid submission and monitoring.

Introduction to Machine Learning, Yandex School of Data Analysis

01/2021 - 02/2021

Intensive 2-week course of machine learning and deep learning methods, via a series of lectures (formal definitions and derivations), seminars (hands-on data analysis) and 2 Kaggle competitions. Included classification, regression, feature selection, dimensionality reduction, feature scaling, clustering and special deep learning topics such as convolutional neural networks and generative adversarial learning. Achieved 94% (top 1 score).

Technology Internship Experience UK, Bright Network

07/2020

Three-day virtual internship programme including seminars on communication and collaboration, creative problem solving and design, agile software development and networking with Accenture, Google, Goldman Sachs, Bloomberg, Amazon and Vodafone representatives. Enterpreneurial team project on delivering Facial Verification in Customer Banking App Sign-In Process.

The Physics of Life Online Summer School, Princeton University

06/2020 - 08/2020

Weekly lectures and discussions of the provided reading material geared towards creating a bridge between undergraduate physics and applications in living systems. Included topics ranging from bacterial and cellular motility to computational neuroscience introduction.

UCL Academic Representative for Natural Sciences

2016 - 2018

Member of Physics and Chemistry Staff-Student Consultative Committees

Leading role within the department to make the student voice heard, enabling communication and helping to promote constructive change, development and enhancement of the programme, making impact on course content, its management and delivery.

UCL Transition Mentor for Natural Sciences

2017 - 2018

Physics Society Parenting Scheme

Positive role model and peer support, facilitating academic sessions, sharing experience.

UCL Interdisciplinary Journal Club

2017 - 2018

Collaborative club for Natural Sciences to meet excellent researchers, learn new analytical techniques, practise presentation skills, and discuss the newest research activities.

Beginners HTML/CSS Web Development Course, Code First Girls

10/2017 - 12/2017

An introduction to web development consisting of fundamental skills of front-end web dev (HTML, CSS, JavaScript), collaborative development with Git and Github, and a team project of creating a website.

UCL Global Citizenship Programme: Justice & Equality

06/2017

Team project based on examining climate change from the perspective of justice (uneven effect distribution) through innovation and entrepreneurship.

DATA ANALYSIS SKILLS

Programming Languages Python, C++, ROOT, Geant4, MATLAB, Mathematica

Software & Tools Jupyter, Github, Git, LaTeX, Excel, Unix.

LANGUAGES

Czech Native Speaker

English Fluent (C1 IELTS Certificate)

German Limited working proficiency (B1 Goethe Institute Certificate)

Russian Elementary proficiency